

CONTACT

4 +40-724-822-801

? Craiova, Romania, EU

in in/sanducosminmihai/

S sandu.cosmin.mihai

SKILLS

PHP 16 years
Symfony 11 years
Git 11 years
Docker 4 years
MySQL 15 years
Jira 16 years
RabbitMQ 6 years
Redis 5 years

EDUCATION

Software Engineer

The University of Craiova 2003 - 2008

Master's degree, Business Management

The University of Craiova 2009 - 2011

LANGUAGES

English Advanced Romanian Native

COSMIN SANDU

Certified Symfony Developer | Senior PHP Developer | Freelancer

About me

I am a Certified Symfony developer / Contractor / Freelancer with over **16+ years of experience**, only interested in #remote work.

I use my expertise, skills, and passion to design and implement top-of-the-line software solutions for companies worldwide.

Drop me a message if you think my expertise could help your organization!

Work experience

Senior Backend Software Developer Foodomarket | B2B Food Marketplace

May 2022 - Present

The client, a startup in B2B food marketplace, was overwhelmed with tasks from business side.

- Leading the backend team + Scrum Master
- Implemented Geo zone microservice
- Implemented Notification service
- Implemented a logging system with live notifications for critical events
- Conducted Security Checks & fixed vulnerabilities
- Migrated main stack to PHP 8
- Migrated secrets to Symfony Vault
- Upgraded Symfony & Sylius versions
- Co-worked on creating a CI pipeline

Skills: Sylius, Symfony, PHP, Git, Docker, MySQL, MariaDB, MongoDB, RabbitMQ, Jira

Technical lead on Symfony Newpharma | SmartValue

April 2021 - May 2022

The client, the first online pharmacy in Belgium, was struggling to maintain their web application and to adapt to changing requirements, due to its outdated legacy code, written without any framework.

- Leading the team to migrate to Symfony framework
- Training the team in Symfony and Unit tests
- Implement a queueing system to handle large loads, ensuring system speed and scalability
- Investigate production loads/performance/issues with the System Architect and DevOps

Skills: Symfony, PHP, Git, Docker, MariaDB, RabbitMQ, Redis, Jira, New Relic, Blackfire

Senior Software Developer eMAG Marketplace

April 2017 - April 2021

The client, the biggest eCommerce company in Romania, was implementing a marketplace where seller's goods are sold on eMAG public website.

- Implement eMAG Marketplace Account Health
- Implement eMAG Marketplace Seller Invoice
- Work on eMAG Finance Application
- Work on eMAG Insurance Application
- Release Manager

Skills: PHP, Symfony, RabbitMQ, Memcache, OpenStack, SOLR, Elasticsearch, Logstash, and Kibana (ELK stack), Redis, MySQL, jQuery, Jenkins

CERTIFICATION

Symfony 6 Certified Dev Symfony RabbitMQ Training Course CloudAMQP

Mastering Relations

Doctrine

SymfonyCasts

Microsoft Certified

Professional

Microsoft

Software Developer NetRom Software

May 2012 - April 2017

The client, the biggest nearshore outsourcing company in Craiova, was creating custom software for there clients - manly based in the Netherlands.

- Implement telecom solution portals using Symfony and CodeIgniter
- Implement SOAP & SOAP Proxy with management applications
- Implement PhoneManager backend (REST)
- Implement fraud management
- Implement healthcare solutions
- Implement job search solution using C#

Skills: PHP, Symfony (1-2-3), Codelgniter, SOAP, REST API, C#, SVN, GIT, jQuery, Bootstrap, Foundation, Jira, Jenkins

Software Quality Assurance

October 2008 - May 2012

NetRom Software

The client, the biggest nearshore outsourcing company in Craiova, was testing custom software for there clients - manly based in the Netherlands.

- Manual testing
- Crawling for rental properties in the Netherlands
- Search Engine Optimization (S.E.O.)
- Automated UI testing with TestComplete (JScript)

Skills: Jira, TestComplete, JScript, SVN, SEO